American Brass Company Records 1997.0996
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
- Series IV: Library Ephemera Files, undated, 1642-1966
  - Subseries C: Anaconda and subsidiaries, undated, 1891-1961
    - Anaconda Aluminum Company (Box 38:176)
      - Personnel, 1952-1960
      - Terre Haute, 1955-1959
    - Anaconda American Brass, Ltd. (Box 39:177)
      - 25th Anniversary, 1947
      - Canada Open House, 1957
      - Employee news, 1959-1960
      - History of Canadian Brass Industry, 1891-1941
      - Informational Brochure, 1957
      - Newspaper clippings, 1930-1960
      - Periodical excerpts, 1931, 1949
      - "Work Year Related to Dollar Income", ca. 1945
    - Anaconda-Jurden Associates, ca. 1958 (Box 39:177)
    - Anaconda Metal Hose Division (Box 39:178)
      - American Metal Hose Company, 1930-1958
      - Announcement and groundbreaking, 1955
      - Charter, 1936
      - General information, 1958-1959
      - Matoon, IL plant, 1955-1958
      - Officers, 1930
      - Open House, 1955-1956
      - Newspaper clippings, 1940-1958
      - Periodical excerpts, 1957, 1959
      - Service Award dinners, 1956-1959
    - Anaconda Wire and Cable (Box 39:178)
      - Development and growth, 1958-1959
      - Newspaper clippings, 1943-1960
      - Office Management, 1959
      - Orange, CA, ca. 1959
      - Patents, 1933-1950
      - Periodical excerpts, 1958-1959
  - Subseries D: Personnel, undated, 1794-1961
    - (Box 39:179)
      - Announcements, 1957-1962
      - Ackerman, James F., 1956-1960
      - Akins, Ellis R., 1958
      - Allcroft, Charles E., 1959
      - Allen, Charles B., 1957-1960
      - Anderson, Carl E., 1958
      - Baker, Robert S., 1929-1952
      - Bassett, Lucius H., 1958-1960
      - Bassett, William H., 1925-1934
      - Bell, Wallace B., 1957
      - Benedict, Ralph T., 1954-1957
      - Besse, William E., 1941, 1954
      - Bleser, Edward M., undated
      - Bradley, John C., 1955
      - Braman, Frederick L., 1941
      - Brewer, Arthur L., 1943, 1958
      - Brimble, Arthur E., 1941-1953
      - Brinckerhoff, Charles M., 1957-1961
      - Brooker, Charles Frederick, 1914-1927
      - Buckbee, H. Allison, 1923-1949
    - (Box 39:180)
      - Campbell, Thomas A., 1955
      - Caples, Russel B., 1953-1959
      - Case, Francis O., 1952-1953
      - Chamberlain, Warren L., 1949
      - Christine, Richard J., 1955-1961
      - Cochran, Archie P., 1959
      - Coe, Herbert W., 1945, 1957
      - Coe, Israel and Demas, 1794-1890, 1940
      - Coe, John Allen, Sr., 1885-1948
        - Testimonial Dinner menu, 1945
    - (Box 39:181)
      - Coe, John Allen Sr.
    - (Box 40:182)
      - Coe, John Allen, Jr., 1944-1960
      - Coe, John Allen, III, 1955-1960
      - Curtis, William S., Jr., 1956
      - Curtiss, Daniel B., 1952
      - Daly, Marcus, 1841-1900
      - Daly, W. Kenneth, 1956-1958
      - Daniel, Claude, 1946
      - Derwin, William J., 1958
      - Donovan, Ralph C., 1955-1957
      - Durfee, Charles P., 1949, 1957
      - Dwyer, Robert E., 1952
      - Eisenwinter, Edward E., 1945, 1948
      - Elton, John Prince, 1948
      - Epley, C. Russell, 1922-1949
      - Erk, Bernhardt W., 1958
      - Erk, Bernhardt W., Jr., 1956, 1960
    - (Box 40:183)
      - Falk, Ernest C., 1949-1957
      - Fitch, Harold D., 1957
      - Flanagan, George F., 1953
      - Foss, Harry C., 1944, 1954
      - Freeman, Alexander B., 1950-1955
      - Freeman, John R., Jr., 1953
      - French, Fred W., 1943
      - French, Leon H., 1955-1960
      - Frisbie, Edward Laurens, 1957
      - Gates, Newman V., 1954
      - Glover, Roy H., 1955-1958
      - Gray, Douglas M., 1955-1960
      - Hammond, William B., 1957
      - Henderson, Donald C., 1958
      - Hickernell, L.F., 1958
      - Hill, Robert H., 1957
      - Hobbins, James R., 1949
      - Holmes, Israel, 1800-1874
      - Hoover, William H., 1946-1952
      - Hull, Daniel R., 1945-1958
      - Hungerford, Charles Stuart, 1945-1957
      - Hungerford, Uri T., 1926
    - (Box 40:184)
      - Judd, Clark S., 1941-1955
      - Jurden, Wilbur, 1958-1960
      - Keeler, Gordon W., 1951-1958
      - Kelley, Cornelius F., 1951-1957
      - Kemp, James T., 1942-1944
      - Knoeppel, William C., 1955-1958
      - Koepel, Norbert, 1959-1960
    - (Box 40:185)
      - Laist, Frederick, 1922
      - Little, Clarence, 1956
      - Lockwood, Justice, 1952-1957
      - McGlone, Edward S., 1946-1957
      - Mackey, Robert U., 1958
      - McNamara, Frank J., 1952-1956
      - Madden, J. Harold, 1943-1958
      - Marvin, James L., 1957-1959
      - Miner, Anson W., 1953
      - Moffatt, William M., 1949-1958
      - Newlin, Richard S., 1958, 1961
      - O'Connor, John J., 1952
      - Parkinson, C. Jay, 1957, 1960
      - Patterson, Scott H., 1952-1960
      - Pendleton, Ethan M., 1954, 1956
      - Perry, Vincent P., 1924-1957
      - Pettigrew, James C., 1960
      - Pierce, Earl V., 1957-1958
      - Poore, Hallis L., 1946
      - Porter, Gordon, 1956
      - Puffer, Richard C., 1953-1960
      - Quigley, Arthur H., 1944-1955
      - Quigley, William E., 1958-1959
    - (Box 40:186)
      - Reihl, Alfred J., 1957
      - Renouard, Edward I., 1951-1959
      - Richardson, Leland R., 1958
      - Rockwell, Allen W., 1956-1959
      - Rockwell, Edwin J., 1950
      - Rowell, John C., 1951-1959
      - Schneider, R. E., 1958
      - Schroeder, Edmond A., 1906-1960
      - Sewell, Frank J., 1956
      - Sheasby, William T., 1953
      - Sims, Frederick G., Jr., 1955
      - Smith, Cyril Stanley [Dr.], 1946-1948
      - Smith, Frank G., 1955
      - Spalding, Samuel C., 1942-1959
      - Steinmetz, Richard B., 1960
      - Stewart, Richard M., 1910-1959
      - Strubell, Gilbert C., 1960
      - Tobin, James E., 1960
    - (Box 40:187)
      - Tracy, Edward B., 1947-1960
    - (Box 40:188)
      - Tully, David E., 1960
      - Vaill, Howard M., 1957
      - Van Riper, Lawson, 1955, 1959
      - Voegeli, Henry E., 1957
      - Wardell, Sydney H., 1949-1958
      - Wayland, Elton S., 1949
      - Weaver, Vincent P., 1955, 1958
      - Weed, Clyde E., 1956, 1959
      - Weed, Herbert M., 1957
      - Wilkinson, Arthur W., 1955
      - Woodward, Carl E., 1949-1959
      - Wright, John A., 1945
  - Subseries E: Directories, 1928-1961
    General note
    [See also: Telephone Directory File (pamphlets).]
    - American Brass Directories (Box 41:189)
      - Main office personnel, 1928
      - Reference directory, 1946
        - Home addresses and telephone numbers
      - Selling personnel, 1939, 1941
      - Telegraph code, 1932
    - American Brass Personnel Directories, 1942-1948 (Box 41:190)
    - American Brass Personnel Directories, 1949-1951 (Box 41:191)
    - American Brass Personnel Directories, 1952-1958 (Box 41:192)
    - Anaconda Personnel Directories, 1952-1961 (Box 41:193)
  - Subseries F: Announcements, undated, 1912-1960
    - American Brass Company (Box 41:194)
      - General office, 1958-1960
      - Obituary notices, 1934-1959
      - Promotions, 1912-1960
      - Retirements, 1943-1958
    - Anaconda Company (Box 41:195)
      - Obituaries, 1947-1959
      - Personnel, 1957-1959
      - Promotions, 1941-1960
      - Retirements, 1957
    - "Men of Anaconda" posters--A - C, undated (Box 42:196)
    - "Men of Anaconda" posters--D - J, undated (Box 42:197)
    - "Men of Anaconda" posters--K - P, undated (Box 42:198)
    - "Men of Anaconda" posters--R - W, undated (Box 42:199)
  - Subseries G: Patent File, undated, 1841-1920
    - (Box 43:200)
      - Index A - Z, 1907-1914
    - (Box 43:201)
      - Shaping of Heated metal 900.401, 1908
      - Extrusion, undated
      - Hydraulic Metal Press 974.195, 1910
      - Machine to make metal bars 770.471, 1904
      - Method of Extruding metal 796.970, 1905
      - Extrusion press 1,037,213, 1912
      - Extrusion machine 1,011,876, 1911
      - Extrusion machine 1,011,522, 1911
      - Apparatus for manufacturing tubes 841,954, 1907
      - Hydraulic metal press, 1910
      - Chase Rolling Mill, 1912
      - Hydraulic apparatus 754,113; 764,412, 1904
      - Hydraulic press and machine, 1907-1908
      - Press for forming tubes 847,635, 1907-1911
      - Making lead pipe 2,296, 1841
      - "Back squirting" a tube 416,014, 1889
      - Method of forming tubes 416,077, 1889
    - (Box 43:202)
      - Method for forming tubes 429,098, 1890
      - "Extrusion" patents, 1891, 1893
      - Shaping metal tubes 481,060, 1892
      - Apparatus for making tubes 493,898, 1893
      - Apparatus for shaping metal tubes, 1893
      - Machine for forming tubes 493,945, 1893
      - Method of reducing tubes or metal, 1894
      - Various patents, undated
      - Extrusion machine 689,668, 1901, 1911
      - Machine for making tin-lined lead pipe 79,549, 1868
      - Ingot forming apparatus 382,427, 1888
      - Extrusion process and machine 896,683; 896,684, 1908
      - Extrusion machine 888,299, 1908
      - Method of casting hollow metal bodies 895,535, 1908
      - Cylinder for treating heated metal 811,196, 1906
      - Cylinder for treating heated metal 834,356, 1906
      - Container for extrusion machine 887,717, 1908
    - (Box 43:203)
      - Extrusion machine 887,718, 1908
      - Apparatus for treating heated metal 819,261, 1906
      - Method of producing seamless hollow bodies, 1910
      - Means of extruding hollow bodies 941,365, 1909
      - "Loomis" machine, 1911
      - Apparatus for manufacturing wire from copper 572,872, 1896
      - Apparatus for treating heated metal 571,265, 1896
      - Manufacture of articles from copper 715,358, 1902
      - Hydraulic press 861,194, 1907
      - Press 924,005, 1909
      - English Schweiger patents 1501/12,847, 1904, 1908
      - Manufacture of plates of sheet metal 962,058, 1910
      - Apparatus for manufacturing metal 861,194, 1904, 1907
    - (Box 43:204)
      - Schweiger machine reports, undated
    - (Box 43:205)
      - Apparatus for making Roll-drawn tubing 631,851, 1899
      - Manufacture of seamless tubular bodies 682,359; 682,360, 1901
      - Cylinder for treating heated metal 811,707, 1906
      - General information, 1907-1912
    - (Box 43:206)
      - Articles on extrusion, 1907-1910
    - (Box 44:207)
      - Die for hot press work, 1913
      - Reports on extrusion process, 1912-1913
      - Pressed metal articles, 1913
      - Manufacture of hollow bodies 1,082,200, 1,082,199, 1908
      - Extrusion machine 1,084,881, 1914
      - Extrusion machine, undated
      - Reports on extrusion machine, 1913
    - (Box 44:208)
      - Report on European trip ( W.W. Cotter), 1913
    - (Box 44:209)
      - Report on European trip ( J. R. Coe), 1914
      - European trip by E.E. Eisenwinter, 1914
      - Agreement-A. Schweiger and ABC, 1911
      - Report on extrusion experiments, 1914
      - Extrusion machine 1,109,555, 1914
      - Extrusion department (Kenosha), 1914
      - Appliance for cutting extrusion rods ( Germany) 265,036, 1913
      - Hydraulic machinery (advertisement), 1916
      - Press for making tubes 1,150,394, 1915
      - Extrusion process 1,199,080, 1916
      - Machine for making seamless tubing 1,330,489, 1920
  - Subseries H: Patent Disputes, 1881-1966
    - Docket 12521, Strip Joint, 1881-1934 (Box 44:210)
    - White, J.J. re Tube reducing machines, 1928-1935 (Box 44:210)
    - Rolling Mill, Housing docket 11,475, 1931-1932 (Box 44:210)
    - Rolling Mill, Steckel, A. P., 1923-1930 (Box 44:211)
    - Rolling Mill, Steckel, A. P., 1930-1959 (Box 44:212)
    - Strip Annealing furnaces, docket 12175, 1932-1933 (Box 44:212)
    - Rolling Mill, Steckel, 1930-1949 (Box 45:213)
    - Steckel Controversy, 1928-1930 (Box 45:214-215)
    - American Brass Company Patents, 1958-1966 (Box 45:216)
    - Eisenwinter, E.E., 1925-1926 (Box 45:216)
    - Schloemann-extrusion equipment, 1943 (Box 45:216)
  - Subseries I: Patent Papers, 1871-1908
    - (Box 45:217)
      - Disputes-Electric lights, 1885
      - #19547, 1897
      - #588,641, 1897
      - #588,649, 1897
      - #887,418, 1908
      - Collapsible block for sheet metal, 1905
      - Machine for rolling copper forms, 1899
      - Patent papers, 1871-1905
    - (Box 45:218)
      - Primer for cartridges, 1882-1883
      - Transfer
        - Charles F. Brooker, 1900-1903
        - Charles H. Harrub, 1882
        - Pocket tobacco cases, 1891-1894
        - Wire drawing machine, 1891-1892
        - William A. Wood, 1905
        - Frederick J. Wooster, 1891-1892
  - Subseries J: Technical Manuals, undated, 1918-1961
    - (Box 46:219)
      - Alloys--Copper, 1927-1961
    - (Box 46:220)
      - Aluminum, 1947-1950
      - Annealing process, 1960
      - Beryllium copper, undated
      - Beta brass, 1941-1942
      - Brass, 1927-1950
      - Bronze, 1928-1950
    - (Box 46:221)
      - Canadian Brass rolling mill, 1934
      - Cartridge brass, 1919
      - Commutator segments, 1954
      - Copper, 1926-1957
      - Copper anodes, 1954
      - Copper wire, 1930-1938
    - (Box 46:222)
      - Cornish engine, 1947
      - Corrosion, 1918-1946
      - Costs, 1929
      - Cupronickel, 1932-1945
      - Electrical conductors, 1938
      - Electro-sheet copper, 1938
      - Everdur, 1939-1941
      - Eyelet machine, 1952
      - Health and safety, 1930-1948
      - Hydraulic system, 1918
      - Inverse segregation, 1941
    - (Box 46:223)
      - Magnesium, undated
      - Non-ferrous metals, 1929-1950
      - Patina, 1934
      - Piping, 1935-1944
      - Silicon Bronze, 1939
      - Steel, 1946
      - Steel rolls, 1946
      - Tubing, 1933-1945
      - Welding, 1929
  - Subseries K: History of the Brass and Cooper Industry, undated, 1790-1961
    - (Box 46:224)
      - American Brass Association reports, 1867
      - American Brass Company, 1868-1954
      - American Flask and Cap Company, 1865-1869
      - Antitrust Probe of Copper and Brass, undated
      - Articles
        - "The Vexations of Revere" Fortune Magazine, 1950
        - Jacobs, C.B. "Copper and Brass in the U.S.A.", 1940
        - Jacobs, C.B. "Development of the Brass Industry", 1939
        - Lathrop, W.G. "The Development of the Brass Industry in Connecticut", 1936
        - Pihl, C.H. "The Birth of Brass in Connecticut", 1952
        - Smith, S.S. "Brass", 1927
      - Benedict & Burnham Manufacturing Company, 1900
      - Beryllium, 1953-1958
      - Bradleyville Iron Mill, Litchfield, CT, 1944, 1952
      - "Brass & Copper" Ency. Americana, 1947
      - Brass Kettle Manufacturing Association, 1885
    - (Box 47:225)
      - Brass Mill history, 1953, 1955
      - Brass wire, price list, 1852
    - (Box 47:226)
      - Bridgeport Brass Company, 1924-1960
      - Bristol Brass Company, 1930-1950
    - (Box 47:227)
      - Bronson Library, 1958-1960
      - Brooker, Charles--letters, 1882, 1893
      - Chamber of Commerce, Nation's Business, 1937
      - Charities, 1950
      - Chase Brass & Copper Co.
        - Files, 1951-1961
        - Personnel, 1936-1960
        - Customers, 1903
      - Chesire Brass Company, undated
    - (Box 47:228)
      - Clocks, 1936-1959
      - Coe Brass Manufacturing Company, 1865
      - Colonial Shopping Plaza, 1960
      - Connecticut, 1944-1960
      - Connecticut Circle, 1958
      - Connecticut industry booklet, ca. 1958
    - (Box 47:229)
      - Copper, 1938-1956
      - Copper and Brass Price Changes, 1959
      - "Copper and Brass" C.M. Depew, undated
      - "Copper and Brass Industry Organization" C.B. Jacobs, 1937
      - Copper mining, 1938
      - Copper mining-- New Jersey, 1953
      - "Copper Outlook", 1851
      - Copper Products Development Association, 1960
      - Crane Company, 1959
      - Daguerreotypes, 1938
      - Dorset-Rex, Inc., 1955-1960
    - (Box 47:230)
      - "Early Trade Associations in the Brass Industry", 1953
      - "Electric Light", 1959
    - (Box 48:231-232)
      - Flood, 1955
    - (Box 48:233)
      - Flood Control plan, 1944
      - Flood-- Torrington, CT, 1955
    - (Box 48:234)
      - Flood-- Waterbury, CT, 1955
      - Flood-- Winsted, CT, 1955
    - (Box 48:235)
      - French Manufacturing Company, 1905-1927
      - Fulling Mill Brook ( Union City, CT), 1937
      - F.W. French Tube Company, 1956-1959
      - Histories of the Brass Industry
        - Jacobs, C.B. "The Copper and Brass Industry", 1937
        - Lathrop. "Brass Industry" (references), 1940
        - Olson, C.E. "History of the Brass Industry in the United States.", 1942
        - Woodward, C.E. Assorted articles on the history of the brass industry, 1952
      - Holmes, Booth and Haydens, 1904
      - Holmes, Hotchkiss, Brown and Elton, 1835
      - Imperial Chemical Industries, Ltd., 1950
    - (Box 48:236)
      - Iron Industry, 1952-1953
      - Judd, Clark S., 1952-1953
      - Kennecott Copper Company, 1957-1960
      - Mattatuck Museum, 1955-1959
      - "Mayflower Aerogram", 1957
      - Metal prices, 1916-1941
      - Middlebury, CT, undated
    - (Box 48:237)
      - Muntz Metal, 1957
      - Nacional de Cobre Earthquake, 1957
      - Naugatuck Brass Industry, Genealogy, 1790-1946
      - Newspaper articles, 1952
      - Patents, 1945-1950
      - Percussion Cap Manufacturers, 1899
      - Phelps Dodge Corporation, 1959
      - Phosphor Bronze, 1957-1959
      - Pipe, 1950
    - (Box 49:238)
      - Revere Copper and Brass, Inc., 1951
      - Revere Copper and Brass, Inc., 1929-1959
      - The River Company--annual reports, 1907, 1908
      - Scovill Manufacturing Company, 1949-1960
    - (Box 49:239)
      - Scovill Manufacturing Company, 1928-1959
    - (Box 49:240)
      - Seymour Manufacturing Company, 1957-1959
      - Seymour Smith Company, 1958
      - Somers Brass Company, Inc., 1959-1960
      - Statistics, 1952
      - Steel, 1957
      - Telephone and Telegraph history, 1957
      - Telephones, 1942
      - Thinsheet Metals Company, 1957
    - (Box 49:241)
      - Thomaston Flood Control Dam, 1956-1960
      - Torrington, CT, 1953-1960
      - Trade Associations, 1953
    - (Box 50:242)
      - Unions, 1959
      - United Fund Campaign, 1953
      - Wallace and Sons, 1900
      - Waterbury Brass Company, 1902
      - Waterbury Button Company, undated
      - Waterbury Clock Company, 1956-1959
      - Waterbury, CT, 1947-1960
    - (Box 50:243)
      - Waterbury, CT--history, 1924-1959
    - (Box 50:244)
      - Waterbury Farrel Foundry and Machine Company, 1951-1960
      - Waterbury Rolling Mills, 1958-1959
      - Waterbury Station, 1951
      - Woodbury, CT--history, 1921-1960
  - Subseries L: Historical Papers, undated, 1881-1961
    - (Box 50:245)
      - Abel Porter & Company history, 1952
      - Advertisement - Postcard, undated
      - American Brass Company-announcements and appointments, 1950-1957
      - American Brass Company and the Anaconda Wire and Cable Company, 1949
    - (Box 50:246)
      - Comparative prices of base metals, 1897-1950
      - Detroit Copper and Brass Rolling Mills - history, 1941, 1950
    - (Box 50:247)
      - Furnace Design and Practice in the USA part 2, 1951
    - (Box 50:248)
      - Jones, Lewis H. - Diary, 1881
    - (Box 50:249)
      - Marquis de Lafayette button description, undated
      - Main Office salaries, 1901-1913
      - Media clippings, 1892-1961
      - Munitions Manufacturers' Tax report, 1917
      - New employee information, undated
      - Preservation of data guidelines, 1958
    - (Box 50:250)
      - Production of material for the U.S. Government, 1945
    - (Box 51:251)
      - Properties of the Detroit Copper and Brass Rolling Mills, 1927
      - Stockholder of the American Brass Company minutes, 1959
      - Time sheet - Brazed Tool Department, 1899
      - U.S. Airforce - relationship to American Industry, 1950
    - (Box 51:252)
      - World War II activities - Anaconda Copper Mining Co., 1949
  - Subseries M: Scrapbooks, undated, 1888-1945
    - Scrapbook, 1924-1928 (Box 52)
    - Scrapbook excerpts, 1933, 1945 (Box 53)
    - Assembled for Charles F. Brooker, Coe Manufacturing Co., 1888-1901 (Box 54)
    - Charles F. Brooker, 1926-1927 (Box 55)
    - Charles F. Brooker, 1899-1908 (Box 56)
- Series V: Papers, Reports, Historical records, and Advertising reprints, undated, 1642-1966
  - Subseries A: Papers and reports, undated, ca. 1906-1968
    - (Box 57:253)
      - American Brass Co.: Number System, ca. 1906
      - Aluminum: Market Survey of Wrought products, 1952
      - American Brass Co.: A Study of our Capabilities Facilities, and Finances with a Reference to Competitive conditions and customer demands, 1956
      - American Ordnance Association Citation, ca. 1962
    - (Box 57:254)
      - Employee Benefits Manual, 1947
    - (Box 57:255)
      - Flood Control-Ansonia, 1967-1968
    - (Box 57:256)
      - "High Sheet Brass Prices", 1925
      - An Interim Report on Discussions covering the Study of Our capabilities and facilities with relation to competitive conditions and customer demands, 1957
      - Litigation, 1911-1952
      - Media Clippings, 1934-1960
      - Production of material for the U.S. Government, 1945
    - (Box 57:257)
      - Proposal on Workmen's Compensation Insurance, 1946
      - Reports and correspondence, 1949-1957
      - Sales forecast, 1964
      - Survey of Strip Aluminum, 1950
  - Subseries B: Historical Records, undated, 1843-1968
    - (Box 58:258)
      - Agreement to continue the Association of the American Brass Manufacturers, 1896
      - "American Brass Ends Subsidiaries" New York Times, 1911
      - Ansonia Clock Co. establishment agreement, 1877
      - Appraisal committee report, 1892
      - Articles of Association, 1867, 1906
    - (Box 58:259)
      - Bank books, undated
      - Benedict, Aaron--memoranda books, 1843-1849
      - Benedict & Burnham--labor contract with J. Adt, 1863
      - Caster's report, 1904
      - Coe Brass Mfg. Co. correspondence
        - Brooker, Charles, 1896
        - Coe, Lyman, 1872
      - Coe, Israel to Henry W. Scovill, 1885
    - (Box 58:260)
      - Engraver's plates, ca. 1880
    - (Box 58:261)
      - Holmes, Booth and Haydens, 1867-1868
      - Letter to Charles Brooker, 1906
      - Licensing Agreement, 1908
    - (Box 58:262)
      - Minutes, 1884-1896
      - Organization charts, ABC and divisions, 1907
    - (Box 59:263)
      - Production, shipment and war bond records, 1945-1950
    - (Box 59:264)
      - Sales and investment papers, 1922-1964
    - (Box 59:265)
      - Stockholder information, 1918-1930
      - Telegraph from New York to Waterbury Brass Co., 1864
      - U.S. Sheet Copper Manufacturers' Association, 1895-1909
    - (Box 59:266)
      - Wire and Cable division financial records, 1928-1930
      - Wiggins Prophecies, 1892
      - Wolcottville Brass Co.--land lease, agreement, 1835, 1841
    - (Box 60:267)
      - Business Study for the Anaconda Company, American Brass Company, Anaconda Wire and Cable Company, 1957
    - (Box 61)
      - "Library Bulletin", 1922-1932
    - (Box 62)
      - Price rulings notebook, 1904-1922
    - (Box 63)
      - Stockholder information, 1899-1930
  - Subseries C: Advertising reprints, undated, 1928-1970
    - Anaconda, 1928 (Box 64)
    - Anaconda, 1929 (Box 65)
    - Advertising reprints, 1952
      - Anaconda American Brass Company (Box 66:268)
      - Bus Conductors (Box 66:269)
      - Condenser Tubes (Box 66:270)
      - Forgings, Extruded Shapes (Box 66:271)
      - Inserts (Box 66:272)
      - Metal Hose (Box 66:273)
      - Pipe and tube (Box 66:274)
      - Rods, wires and bars (Box 66:275)
      - Sewage and water works (Box 66:276)
      - Sheet and strip (Box 66:277)
      - Welding rods (Box 66:278)
    - Advertising reprints, 1953
      - Anaconda American Brass Company (Box 66:279)
      - Bus conductors (Box 66:280)
      - Condenser tubes (Box 66:281)